ABOUTME

I am a software developer who has worked on web based applications which includes warehousing and ERP. My experience is on developing dynamic front-end UI on angular, laravel and databases (Oracle), as well as providing IT support and maintenance.

CONTACT

- mikeodida@gmail.com
- (+254)706 82 33 76

Nairobi, Kenya



EDUCATION

- STRATHMORE UNIVERSITY
 Bachelor in Business
 Information Technology
 2022 completed waiting for
 graduation 2023. Expected
 Second Class Honours (lower
- SIHAY SECONDARY SCHOOL KCSE 2015 mean grade B-Math's – B (Plain) Eng.– C (Plain)

MICHAEL OMONDI ODIDA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic and hard-working in system development, computer networking, software installation & maintenance, and also graphic design. I have 2+ years of professional experience in coding and brand development. I enjoy coding, testing, integration and IT support. Seeking a new challenges and opportunities to leverage.

EXPERIENCE

German Doctors Nairobi as an Intern (2020 - 2022)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Responsibilities

- Taking on small software development projects then presenting my work to the leadership team.
- Designing all solutions to follow MVC architecture and designing all models, views using media queries and bootstrap to ensure responsive, user experience.
- I have created the German Doctors website
 <u>www.germandoctorsnairobi.co.ke</u>
 , and more for individuals to manage their ecommerce businesses and systems for managing screened patient for the Eligibility using laravel PHP.
- I have also developed an Asset Management sytem for German Doctors and Linda Binti project.
- Overseeing software applications as a project manager using Waterfall Agile process models.
- Assisting with process improvements, making suggestions on workplan changes where needed.
- Documenting all changes which have been made in the system.

Referees

Elijah Magongo Strategic Information, at German Doctors Nairobi Contacts: +254720565824 Magongo.elijah@gmail.com

Thomas Nyambura
International Affairs,
Strathmore University
Contacts: +254790554590
tnyambura@strathmore.edu

Mohamed Andala, Teacher at Sihay High School Contacts: +254724879976

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

German Doctors Nairobi as an Intern Responsibilities

(2020 - 2022)

- Designed calendars and Christmas cards.
- Designed business cards for the organization for senior staffs.
- Designed visual content for Facebook and Instagram posts, which in total received more points of engagement.

IT HELP DESK ASSOCIATED

German Doctors Nairobi as an Intern Responsibilities

(2020-2022)

- Installed, serviced and upgraded over 20 Windows computers.
- Provided PC and mobile support to resolve client issues.
- Assisted the network team in monitoring network servers.
- Delivering troubleshooting solutions to departments and console operators experiencing difficulties with the software, hardware and network connectivity e.g. cabling point to end point.
- Drive enhanced performance figures for the IT team and department to meet stated management expectations and relevant standards.
- Also providing IT security in the organization e.g. Network security and systems.

IT SPECIALITIES

- query languages(Oracle PL/SQL, SQL),
- Software Development
- Adobe (illustrator, photoshop)
- Network Administration
- Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP)
- Web Development
- Problem Solving
- Linux User (Ubuntu)
- Business Intelligence
- Database Administration
- Social media and web analytics tools including Facebook Insights,
 Google Analytics,